quip.com 2018-10-27

# Quip

Quip LLC and its parent, salesforce.com, inc. (together, “we,” “us,” “our”, “Company” or “Quip”) are committed to protecting the privacy of individuals who visit the Company’s Web sites (“Visitors”), individuals who register to use the Services as defined below (“Customers”), and individuals who register to attend the Company’s corporate events (“Attendees”). This Privacy Statement describes Quip’s privacy practices in relation to the use of the Company’s Web sites and the related applications and services offered by Quip (collectively, the “Services”).

This Privacy Statement explains our practices regarding the collection, use and disclosure of information that we receive when you use Quip, as well as your choices regarding use, access and correction of your personal information.

#### 1\. Web sites covered

This Privacy Statement covers the information practices of Web sites that link to this Privacy Statement, including the website and platform available at <https://www.quip.com/> (collectively referred to as “Quip Web sites” or “the Company’s Web sites”).

Quip’s Web sites may contain links to other Web sites. The information practices or the content of such other Web sites is governed by the privacy statements of such other Web sites. The Company encourages you to review the privacy statements of other Web sites to understand their information practices.

#### 2\. Information collected

When expressing an interest in obtaining additional information about the Services, or registering to use the Web sites or other services, or registering for an event, Quip requires you to provide the Company with personal contact information, such as name, company name, address, phone number, zip code and email address (“Required Contact Information”). When purchasing the Services or registering for an event, Quip may also require you to provide the Company with financial qualification and billing information, such as billing name and address, credit card number, and the number of employees within the organization that will be using the Services (“Billing Information”). Quip may also ask you to provide additional information, such as company annual revenues, number of employees, industry or to enhance information on a user profile, gender (“Optional Information”). When Visitors apply for a job with the Company, Quip may also require you to submit additional personal information as well as a resume or curriculum vitae (“Applicant Information”). If you choose to create a Quip account via a third-party service, you may have to provide us with information such as your username or email for your account with the third party so that your identity can be authenticated and when the authentication is complete, we’ll be able to access certain information based on your permissions from the third-party service (“Authentication Information”). Through our “import contacts” feature option, we may also collect information such as the name, company name, address, phone number or email address of contacts that you choose to share with us (“Import Information”). Our servers automatically record information about how a person uses Quip, including Internet Protocol (“IP”) addresses, browser types, operating systems, pages or features of Quip that were used and time spent on them, date/time stamp, search terms, in some cases we collect and store information about where you are located, such as by converting your IP address into a rough geolocation, and other statistics (“Information about Use of Quip”). Required Contact Information, Billing Information, Applicant Information, Optional Information, Authentication Information, Import Information, Information about Use of Quip, and any other information you submit to Quip or through the Services are referred to collectively as “Data.”

As you navigate the Company’s Web sites, Quip may also collect information through the use of commonly-used information-gathering tools, such as cookies and Web beacons (“Web Site Navigational Information”). Web Site Navigational Information includes standard information from your Web browser (such as browser type and browser language), your IP address, and the actions you take on the Company’s Web sites (such as the Web pages viewed and the links clicked). For additional information about the collection of Web Site Navigational Information by Quip and others, please see Section entitled “Web Site Navigational Information” below.

#### 3\. Use of information collected

The Company uses Data about Quip Customers to perform the services requested. For example, if you fill out a “Contact Me” Web form, the Company will use the information provided to contact you about your interest in the Services.

The Company uses Data about Quip Attendees to plan and host corporate events, host online forums and social networks in which event attendees may participate, and to populate online profiles for Attendees on the Company’s Web sites. Additional information on the Company’s privacy practices with respect to Data about Quip Attendees may be found in additional privacy statements on the event Web sites, as the case may be. Please see Section below entitled “Public forums, refer a friend, and customer testimonials” for more information on bulletin boards, blogs, or chat rooms provided by Quip in connection with its corporate events.

The Company may also use Data about Quip Customers and Data about Quip Attendees for marketing purposes. For example, the Company may use information you provide to contact you to further discuss your interest in the Services and to send you information regarding the Company, its affiliates, and its partners, such as information about promotions or events.

Quip uses Billing Information to check the financial qualifications and collect payment from prospective and current Customers and Attendees.

Quip uses Web Site Navigational Information to operate and improve the Company’s Web sites or Services. The Company may also use Web Site Navigational Information alone or in combination with Data about Quip Customers and Data about Quip Attendees to provide personalized information about the Company. For additional information about the use of Web Site Navigational Information, please see Section entitled “Web Site Navigational Information” below.

Quip uses Applicant Information, Import Information, and Authentication Information for the limited reason for which it is provided to Us, such as to find someone you know using Quip or to add someone to your site. If you believe that one of your contacts has provided us with your personal information and you would like to request that it be removed from our database, please contact us [here](https://pages.mail.salesforce.com/contact-privacy/).

Quip uses information about use of Quip (and may engage third parties to analyze)to customize and improve Quip. We also use IP addresses to generate aggregate, non-identifying information about how Quip is used, and if such IP address is converted into a rough geolocation, we may use such location information to improve and personalize Quip.

#### 4\. Web Site Navigational Information, Cookies, Web Beacons and IP Addresses

Quip uses commonly-used information-gathering tools, such as cookies, Web beacons, or similar technologies, to collect information from your computer or mobile device as you navigate the Company’s Web sites (“Web Site Navigational Information”). This section describes the types of Web Site Navigational Information used on the Company’s Web sites and how this information may be used.

##### Cookies

Quip.com uses cookies to make interactions with the Company’s Web sites easy and meaningful. When you visit one of the Company’s Web sites, our servers send a cookie to your computer. Standing alone, cookies do not personally identify you; they merely recognize your Web browser. Unless you choose to identify yourself to us, either by responding to a promotional offer, opening an account, or filling out a Web form (such as a “Contact Me” or a “30 Day Free Trial” Web form), you will not be personally identified by the Company.

Quip.com uses cookies that are session—based and persistent—based. Session cookies exist only during one session. They disappear from your computer when you close your browser software or turn off your computer. Persistent cookies remain on your computer after you close your browser or turn off your computer. Please note that if you disable your Web browser’s ability to accept cookies, you will be able to navigate the Company’s Web sites, but you will not be able to successfully use the Services.

The following sets out how we use different categories of cookies and your options for managing cookies’ settings:

Type of Cookies| Description| Managing Settings  
---|---|---  
  
 **Required cookies**

| 

Required cookies enable you to navigate the Company’s Web sites and use its features, such as accessing secure areas of the Web sites and using Quip Services.  
If you have chosen to identify yourself to Quip, the Company uses cookies containing encrypted information to allow the Company to uniquely identify you. Each time you log into the Services, a cookie containing an encrypted, unique identifier that is tied to your account is placed on your browser. These cookies allow the Company to uniquely identify you when you are logged into the Services and to process your online transactions and requests.

| 

Because required cookies are essential to operate the Company’s Web sites and the Services, there is no option to opt out of these cookies.  
  
 **Performance cookies**

| 

These cookies collect information about how Visitors use our Web site, including which pages visitors go to most often and if they receive error messages from certain pages. These cookies do not collect information that individually identifies a Visitor. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and anonymous. It is only used to improve how the Company’s Web site functions and performs.  
From time—to—time, Quip engages third parties to track and analyze usage and volume statistical information from individuals who visit the Company’s Web sites. Quip may also utilize Flash cookies for these purposes.

| 

To learn how to opt out of performance cookies using your browser settings [click here](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).   
To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies [click here](https://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html).  
  
 **Functionality cookies**

| 

Functionality cookies allow the Company’s Web sites to remember information you have entered or choices you make (such as your username, language, or your region) and provide enhanced, more personal features. These cookies also enable you to optimize your use of Quip’s Services after logging in. These cookies can also be used to remember changes you have made to text size, fonts and other parts of web pages that you can customize.Quip uses local shared objects, also known as Flash cookies, to store your preferences or display content based upon what you view on Company Web sites to personalize your visit.

| 

To learn how to opt out of functionality cookies using your browser settings [click here](http://www.aboutcookies.org/). Note that opting out may impact the functionality you receive when visiting Company Web sites.   
To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies [click here](https://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html).  
  
 **Targeting or Advertising cookies**

| 

From time—to—time, Quip engages third parties to track and analyze usage and volume statistical information from individuals who visit the Company’s Web sites. Quip sometimes uses cookies delivered by third parties to track the performance of Company advertisements. For example, these cookies remember which browsers have visited the Company’s Web sites. The information provided to third parties does not include personal information, but this information may be re—associated with personal information after the Company receives it.  
Quip also contracts with third—party advertising networks that collect IP addresses and other information from Web beacons (see below) on the Company’s Web sites, from emails, and on third—party Web sites. Ad networks follow your online activities over time and across different sites or other online services by collecting Web Site Navigational Information through automated means, including through the use of cookies. These technologies may recognize you across the different devices you use, such as a desktop or laptop computer, smartphone or tablet. Third parties use this information to provide advertisements about products and services tailored to your interests. You may see these advertisements on other Web sites or mobile applications on any of your devices. This process also helps us manage and track the effectiveness of our marketing efforts. Third parties, with whom the Company partners to provide certain features on Company Web sites or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity, use Flash cookies to collect and store information. Flash cookies are different from browser cookies because of the amount of, type of, and how data is stored.

| 

To learn more about these and other advertising networks and their opt out instructions, click [here](https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) and [here](http://optout.aboutads.info/#/).   
To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies [click here](https://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html).  
  
##### Web Beacons

Quip uses Web beacons alone or in conjunction with cookies to compile information about Customers and Visitors’ usage of the Company’s Web sites and interaction with emails from the Company. Web beacons are clear electronic images that can recognize certain types of information on your computer, such as cookies, when you viewed a particular Web site tied to the Web beacon, and a description of a Web site tied to the Web beacon. For example, Quip may place Web beacons in marketing emails that notify the Company when you click on a link in the email that directs you to one of the Company’s Web sites. Quip uses Web beacons to operate and improve the Company’s Web sites and email communications.

The Services may be used by our Customers to collect certain information about individuals and their online activities, such as interactions with a Customer’s online content and electronic communications. Our Services use cookies and other tracking technologies to allow our Customers to understand how you interact with their content and electronic communications. Customers are responsible for complying with any legal requirements in using any tracking technologies made available through the Services, including complying with any notice and consent requirements, informing individuals on how to opt-out from certain technologies, and disclosing the use of such technologies in their respective privacy statements.

##### IP Addresses

When you visit the Company's Web sites, the Company collects your Internet Protocol (“IP”) addresses to track and aggregate non-personal information. For example, Quip uses IP addresses to monitor the regions from which Customers and Visitors navigate the Company’s Web sites. Quip also collects IP addresses from Customers when they log into the Services as part of the Company’s “Identity Confirmation” and “IP Range Restrictions” security features. Quip.com also collects IP addresses from Customers when they log into the Services as part of the Company’s “Identity Confirmation” and “IP Range Restrictions” security features.

##### Social Media Features

The Company’s Web sites may use social media features, such as the Facebook ‘like’ button (“Social Media Features”). These features may collect your IP address and which page you are visiting on the Company’s Web site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. You may be given the option by such Social Media Features to post information about your activities on the Company’s Web site to a profile page of yours that is provided by a third party Social Media network in order to share with others within your network. Social Media Features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on the Company’s Web site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing the relevant Social Media Features.

##### Do Not Track

Currently, various browsers — including Internet Explorer, Firefox, and Safari — offer a “do not track” or “DNT” option that relies on a technology known as a DNT header, which sends a signal to Web sites’ visited by the user about the user's browser DNT preference setting. Quip does not currently commit to responding to browsers' DNT signals with respect to the Company's Web sites, in part, because no common industry standard for DNT has been adopted by industry groups, technology companies or regulators, including no consistent standard of interpreting user intent. Quip takes privacy and meaningful choice seriously and will make efforts to continue to monitor developments around DNT browser technology and the implementation of a standard.

##### Advertising

We also partner with a third party to display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partners may use cookies or similar technologies in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising click [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/), or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). Please note you will continue to receive generic ads.

##### 5\. Public Forums, Refer a Friend, and Customer Testimonials

Quip may provide bulletin boards, blogs, or chat rooms on the Company’s Web sites. Any personal information you choose to submit in such a forum may be read, collected, or used by others who visit these forums, and may be used to send you unsolicited messages. Quip is not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these forums.

Customers and Visitors may elect to use the Company’s referral program to inform friends about the Company’s Web sites. When using the referral program, the Company requests the friend’s name and email address. Quip will automatically send the friend a one–time email inviting him or her to visit the Company’s Web sites. Quip does not store this information.

Quip posts a list of Customers and testimonials on the Company’s Web sites that contain information such as Customer names and titles. Quip obtains the consent of each Customer prior to posting any information on such a list or posting testimonials.

#### 6\. Sharing of information collected

##### Service Providers

Quip may share Data about Quip Visitors, Customers and Attendees with the Company’s contracted service providers so that these service providers can provide services on our behalf. Without limiting the foregoing, Quip may also share Data about Quip Visitors, Customers and Attendees with the Company’s service providers to ensure the quality of information provided, and with third–party social networking and media Web sites, such as Facebook, for marketing and advertising on those Web sites. Unless described in this Privacy Statement, Quip does not share, sell, rent, or trade any information with third parties for their promotional purposes. A service provider providing services on our behalf is authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

##### Quip.com Affiliates

The Company may share Data about Quip Customers with other companies in order to work with them, including affiliates of the Salesforce corporate group. For example, the Company may need to share Data about Quip Customers for customer relationship management, technical operations, marketing and account management purposes.

##### Business Partners

From time to time, Quip may partner with other companies to jointly offer products or services, such as our AppExchange partners. If you download, purchase or specifically express interest in a jointly–offered product or service from or through Quip, the Company may share Data about Quip Customers collected in connection with your download, purchase or expression of interest with our partner(s). Quip does not control our business partners’ use of the Data about Quip Customers we collect, and their use of the information will be in accordance with their own privacy policies. If you do not wish for your information to be shared in this manner, you may opt not to download, purchase or specifically express interest in a jointly offered product or service.

Quip does not share Data about Quip Attendees with business partners unless: (1) you specifically opt in to such sharing via an event registration form; or (2) you attend a Company event and allow Quip or any of its designees to scan your attendee badge. If you do not wish for your information to be shared in this manner, you may choose not to opt in via event registration forms and elect not to have your badge scanned at Company events. If you choose to share your information with business partners in the manners described above, your information will be subject to the business partners’ respective privacy statements.

##### Third Parties

Section 4 of this Privacy Statement, Web Site Navigational Information, specifically addresses the information we or third parties collect through cookies, web beacons, and similar tracking technologies, and how you can control cookies through your Web browsers.

##### Billing

Quip uses a third-party service provider to manage credit card processing. This service provider is not permitted to store, retain, or use Billing Information except for the sole purpose of credit card processing on the Company’s behalf. Any billing service provider providing services on our behalf is authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

##### Compelled Disclosure

Quip reserves the right to use or disclose information provided if required by law or if the Company reasonably believes that use or disclosure is necessary to protect the Company’s rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process.

##### Your Request

If you expressly ask us to do so, or give us your prior consent to do so, we may disclose information provided to a third party.

##### Aggregate and Anonymous Information

We may share aggregated,non-identifying information with third parties for industry analysis, demographic profiling and other similar purposes.

#### 7\. International transfer of information collected

The Company primarily stores Data about Quip Customers and Data about Quip Attendees in the United States. To facilitate Quip’s global operations, the Company may transfer and access such information from around the world, including from other countries in which the Company has operations. This Privacy Statement shall apply even if Quip transfers Data about Quip Customers or Data about Quip Attendees to other countries.

#### 8\. Communications preferences

Quip offers Visitors, Customers, and Attendees who provide contact information a means to choose how the Company uses the information provided. You may update your email preferences by using the “Unsubscribe” link found in emails we send to you, by accessing your account profile on our website, or by contacting us as described below.

#### 9\. Correcting and updating your information

You may access, correct or request deletion of Data We have about You by logging into your account. You may also request cancellation of your account by contacting us [here](https://www.salesforce.com/form/contact/contact-privacy.jsp?display_type=lb&contentWidth=420&contentPadding=30). We’ll take steps to delete your information within a reasonable timeframe, but some information may remain in archived/backup copies for our records or as otherwise required by law.

If personal information pertaining to you as an individual has been submitted to us by a Quip Customer and you wish to exercise any rights you may have to access, correct, amend, or delete such data, please inquire with our Customer directly. Because Quip personnel have limited ability to access data our Customers submit to our services, if you wish to make your request directly to Quip, please contact us [here](https://www.salesforce.com/form/contact/contact-privacy.jsp?display_type=lb&contentWidth=420&contentPadding=30) and provide the name of the Quip Customer who submitted your data to our services. We will refer your request to that Customer, and will support them as needed in responding to your request within a reasonable timeframe.

#### 10\. Customer Data

Quip’s Customers may electronically submit data or information to the Services for hosting and processing purposes (“Customer Data”). Quip handles Customer Data in accordance with a Service’s terms of service or a subscription agreement in place between Quip and our Customers, which exclusively govern the Company’s treatment of Customer Data and supersede this Privacy Statement in case of conflict, or as required by law. In general, Quip may access Customer Data only for the purpose of providing the Services, preventing or addressing service or technical problems, or as may be required by law. Additional information about the Company’s privacy and security practices with respect to Customer Data is available [here](https://help.salesforce.com/apex/HTViewSolution?urlname=Trust-and-Compliance-Documentation&language=en_US).

#### 11\. Security

Quip uses robust security measures to protect Data about Quip Customers and Data about Quip Attendees. Because the Company uses the Services to maintain Data about Salesforce Customers and Data about Salesforce Attendees, this information, which is stored in the Services, is secured in the same manner as described [here](https://help.salesforce.com/apex/HTViewSolution?urlname=Trust-and-Compliance-Documentation&language=en_US). We may retain Data for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.

#### 12\. Mobile applications

Without limiting the generality of this Privacy Statement, in addition to information gathered through its Web sites or submitted to its Services, Quip may obtain information through applications (“Mobile Applications”) that Customers or their authorized individuals (“Users”) download to, and run on, their mobile devices (“Devices”). Mobile Applications provided by Quip may obtain information from, or access data stored on, Users’ Devices to provide services related to the relevant Mobile Application. For example, a Mobile Application may: access a camera on a User’s Device to enable the User to upload photographs to the Services; access the call history on a User’s Device to enable the User to upload that information to the Services; access calendar information on a User’s Device to enable the User to match meeting attendees with contacts submitted by the User to the Services; access the geographic location of a User’s Device to enable the User to identify contacts submitted by the User the Services who are nearby; or access contact information on a User’s Device to enable the User to sync contact information between the information that is stored on the User’s Device and the information that is submitted to the Services. Information obtained to provide Mobile Application services may include information obtained in preparation for anticipated updates to those services. Mobile Applications may transmit information to and from Devices to provide the Mobile Application services.

Mobile Applications may provide Quip with information related to Users’ use of the Mobile Application services, information regarding Users’ computer systems, and information regarding Users’ interaction with Mobile Applications, which Quip may use to provide and improve the Mobile Application services. For example, all actions taken in a Mobile Application may be logged, along with associated information (such as the time of day when each action was taken). Quip may also share anonymous data about these actions with third party providers of analytics services. In addition, if a User downloads a Quip Mobile Application after clicking on a third-party mobile advertisement for the Mobile Application or for Quip, the third-party advertiser may provide Quip with certain information, such as the User’s Device identification information, which Quip may use to track the performance of its advertising campaigns.

Customers may configure Quip Mobile Application services, and the information accessed or obtained by the Mobile Application on a User’s Device may be affected by the Customer’s configuration. In addition, if a Customer downloads and/or purchases more than one Service from Quip and its affiliates, a Mobile Application may be designed to interoperate with those Services; for instance, to provide a User with access to information from any or all of those Services or to provide information from a User’s Device to any or all of those Services. Information accessed or obtained by the Mobile Application on a User’s Device may be accessible to the Customer and its organization, depending on the intended functionality of the Mobile Application. In addition to Mobile Applications offered by Quip, the Company may offer platforms for the creation of third-party Mobile Applications. Third parties may obtain information from, or access data stored on, Users’ Devices to provide services associated with any third-party Mobile Applications that Users download, install, use, or otherwise interact with over a Quip platform. Quip’s Mobile Applications may also contain links or integrations to other Mobile Applications provided by third parties. Third parties’ use of information collected through third-party Mobile Applications is governed by the privacy statements of such third parties. The Company encourages you to review the privacy statements of third-party providers of Mobile Applications to understand their information practices.

Notices and contractual terms related to a particular Mobile Application may be found in the End User License Agreement or relevant terms of service for that application. The Company encourages you to review the End User License Agreement or relevant terms of service related to any Mobile Applications you download, install, use, or otherwise interact with to understand that Mobile Application’s information practices. The Mobile Application’s access to information through a User’s Device does not cause that information to be "Customer Data" under Quip’s Master Subscription Agreement with the Customer or under this Privacy Statement, except as follows: To the extent that a User uses a Mobile Application to submit electronic data and information to a Customer account on our Services pursuant to the Customer's Master Subscription Agreement with Quip (or a similar agreement that governs the Customer’s subscription(s) to Quip’s Services), that information constitutes “Customer Data” as defined in such agreement, and the provisions of that agreement with respect to privacy and security of such data will apply.

#### 13\. EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and U.S.-Swiss Privacy Shield Framework

The Services comply with the EU–U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States, respectively. Salesforce has certified to the Department of Commerce that the Services adhere to the Privacy Shield Principles. You can view a description of how we comply with the Privacy Shield Principles in our [Privacy Shield Notice](http://www.salesforce.com/assets/pdf/misc/privacy-shield-notice.pdf). To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, please visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield website [here](https://www.privacyshield.gov/); to view our certification, search for “Salesforce.”

If you have questions or complaints regarding this Privacy Statement or associated practices, please contact us [here](https://www.salesforce.com/form/contact/contact-privacy.jsp?display_type=lb&contentWidth=420&contentPadding=30). If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

Any questions, comments or complaints about the data practices (including compliance with data privacy principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, access, security, data integrity or enforcement) of our Services' Customers or partners for which Salesforce processes data should be addressed to that Customer or partner.

#### 14\. Changes to this Privacy Statement

Quip reserves the right to change this Privacy Statement. Quip will provide notification of the material changes to this Privacy Statement through the Company’s Web sites prior to the change taking effect.

#### 15\. Contacting us

Questions regarding this Privacy Statement or the information practices of the Company’s Web sites should be directed to Quip Privacy by contacting us [here](https://www.salesforce.com/form/contact/contact-privacy.jsp?display_type=lb&contentWidth=420&contentPadding=30) or mail us at:

Salesforce Data Protection Officer  
The Landmark @ One Market Street, Suite 300  
San Francisco, CA 94105
